doyoubuzz.com 2018-12-10

# DoYouBuzz : Privacy Policy

1\. Acceptance of the Privacy Policy

2\. Information collected or received

3\. Registration, account setup and use of Services

4\. Resume data

5\. Personal information and professional objectives

6\. Email, email address and anonymous telephone number

7\. Proofreading of resume

8\. Automated information

9\. Analytics

10\. Information from third parties

11\. Information relative to non-users

12\. Choice and control

13\. Payment information

14\. Communicating with DoYouBuzz

15\. Usage, sharing, and disclosure of information

16\. Security

17\. Information Retention

18\. Security Backups

19\. Your rights

20\. Withdrawal of consent

21\. Amendments to the Privacy Policy

22\. Contact us

##  1\. Acceptance of the Privacy Policy 

In order to manage our business and provide you with our Services, we must process your personal information. By accepting our Terms of Use, you confirm that you have read and understood this policy, including how and why we use your information. If you do not wish for us to collect or process your personal information in the manner described in this policy, you should not use our Services. We are not responsible for the content posted by our members, third-party websites or third-party applications. By using these Services, you agree that DoYouBuzz will use your information in France and in any other country where DoYouBuzz operates.   

##  2\. Information collected or received 

As part of our Services, we collect and receive your personal information in several different ways. You can often choose the information you provide, but it is sometimes necessary for us to obtain specific information in order to allow you to use our Services and to enable us to provide them to you.   

##  3\. Registration, account setup and use of Services

In order to use our Services, you must provide us with a valid email address, the first and last name associated with your account which you may choose and which represents your identity on DoYouBuzz. You can review, modify or delete this name in your account settings.   

This information is necessary for us to provide you with our Services. Depending on the Services you choose to use, we may require additional information in order to supply you with information, such as a resume name, phone number, mailing address or payment information to access paid services.   

##  4\. Resume data 

You may provide data that will allow us to put together your resume, such as your photo, date of birth, phone numbers or other contact information (Skype, etc.), city of residence (address, zip code, country), past experience (job title, dates, contract types, company name, projects worked on, results obtained, etc.), education/training (name of school, degree/diploma, education/training description, date of training/education), skills (type, title, level of knowledge, detailed description), hobbies, keywords, links to external profiles (LinkedIn profile, GitHub, etc.), personal statement, etc. You can delete or modify this information at any time by logging into your account. 

##  5\. Personal information and professional objectives

In order to allow us to personalize your user experience and to allow you to send your resume to our resume partners, you may provide us with with personal information such as your nationality, postal address, level of education/training, number of years of professional experience and whether or not you own a personal vehicle. For the same reasons, you can also indicate your professional objective, your geographic mobility (country, city, zone), your industry, the function(s) you would like to perform, the type of contract you are looking for, the number of hours you are looking for, the frequency of travel and the pay you are seeking.   

You can, at any time, delete or modify this information. Please note, however, that some of this information is necessary in order to send your resume to employment sites (a notification will be provided to you at the time of sending if any of this data is missing). In this regard, we remind you that sending your resume to partner sites is a voluntary action on your part.   

##  6\. Email, email address and anonymous telephone number

DoYouBuzz allows you to send and receive emails in order to help you in your job search. To provide this service, DoYouBuzz stores email addresses, first and last names of people you communicate with, message content (text and attachments), date and time sent and recipients’ actions with respect to the messages (opening the email and clicking on links).   

DoYouBuzz also allows you to post an anonymous email address (under the format of firstname-lastname@doyoubuzz.io), as well as an anonymous phone number to protect against the distribution of your email address as well as your phone number.   

You may decide not to use these features by deleting the contact form on your resume, and by disabling the “keep my email private” option and/or the “keep my phone number private” option. 

##  7\. Proofreading of resume 

To allow your contacts to send you suggestions for improving your resume, we need to store their suggestions, first name, last name, and email address. 

##  8\. Automated information

DoYouBuzz automatically receives and records from your browser or mobile device when you visit the Site or use the Applications or various other Services, as well as information such as your IP address or your device’s unique identifier and cookies and information on the pages you visit, in order to allow us to manage and provide our Services. This information is stored in log files and is automatically collected. We may combine this information collected from your browser or mobile device with other information we or our partners collect on you from all devices. This information is used to prevent fraud and maintain the security of our Services, to analyze and understand how the Services work for members and visitors and to offer a more personalized experience for members and visitors. 

##  9\. Analytics  

We use data analysis technologies to ensure operation of the site, improve our Services, and send you personalized suggestions according to your usage. We use analytics software to help us understand how you use our Services. These programs may record information such as the frequency with which you use our Services, what transpires within the use of the Services, your cumulative usage rates, performance data, errors that occurred (which may sometimes contain information such as your first name, last name, email address, and other information you have provided to us), as well as debugging information.   

We may also collect information relative to your use of our Services for advertising, analytics, content distribution and protecting our Services, including your IP address and browser information (including referrals).   

We may also automatically collect device-specific information when you install, access or use our Services. This information may include the hardware model, operating system details, usage, debugging information, browser and IP address.   

##  10\. Information from third parties 

Some users or visitors may choose to connect to DoYouBuzz or to create a DoYouBuzz account using a third-party application, such as Facebook or an application developed using the DoYouBuzz API. DoYouBuzz may receive information from the connected third-party applications. Connecting your account to third-party applications or services is optional. If you choose to connect your account to a third-party application, DoYouBuzz may receive information from that application. We may also collect public information to contact you. We may use this information in the course of providing Services.

##  11\. Information relative to non-users 

DoYouBuzz may receive or obtain information (for example, an email address or an IP address) on someone who is not yet a user of DoYouBuzz (a “non-user”) in connection with certain features of DoYouBuzz, such as when a non-user chooses to subscribe to a DoYouBuzz newsletter, a user invites a non-user to proofread their resume, a user communicates with a non-user via the DoYouBuzz email feature or the anonymous email address, or a non-user uses the anonymous phone number to call a user. Non-user information is used only to allow actions authorized by the non-user.   

##  12\. Choice and control 

DoYouBuzz allows you the choice to provide, modify or delete certain information. You can modify or correct your DoYouBuzz account information in your account settings. You can also delete certain optional information that you no longer wish to share publicly.   

You may also request the deletion of all personal information from your account.   

##  13\. Payment information

As part of your payment information, DoYouBuzz does not store your credit card information. This information is transmitted to our sub-contractors, who ensure its confidentiality. DoYouBuzz only stores meta-data, which allows us to communicate with our payment sub-processors. 

##  14\. Communicating with DoYouBuzz 

You may also control the receipt of certain types of communication from DoYouBuzz in your account preferences. DoYouBuzz may send you messages regarding its Services or your activity. Some of these messages are necessary, as they relate to services intended for users (such as transaction messages or legal messages). Other messages, such as newsletters, are not necessary. You may choose which optional messages you wish to receive by modifying your account settings. 

If you no longer wish to use our Services or receive messages relating to the Services (with the exception of notifications required by law), you can close your account.   

Upon occasion, DoYouBuzz may need to contact you. These messages are essentially sent by email or by instant notification, and each account must be linked to a valid email address in order to receive these messages. DoYouBuzz may also contact you by telephone to provide member support or in connection with a transaction if you ask us to call you.   

Certain messages from DoYouBuzz are related to services and are necessary for users. You agree that DoYouBuzz may send you emails or messages for non-marketing purposes, i.e. those concerning transactions, your account, security, or product changes. Some examples of service-related messages: an email address confirmation, a welcome email upon setting up your account, an order notification, the availability of a service, changes to key features, and communication with the DoYouBuzz customer support team.   

When you create an account, you subscribe to email notifications and agree to receive emails and marketing messages from us. You can unsubscribe from marketing emails at any time via the unsubscribe link contained in marketing-related emails or messages. Members can also manage the sending of certain marketing emails or messages via their account settings, as well as via the unsubscribe link contained in marketing emails or messages.   

##  15\. Usage, sharing, and disclosure of information   

When you access or use our Services, we collect, use, share and process your personal information as described in this policy. We rely on a number of legal grounds to use your information in this way. These legal grounds include cases where:   

  * these uses are necessary for fulfilling the contractual obligations stated in our Terms of Use, and to provide you with our Services;
  * you have agreed to these uses and can withdraw consent at any time; 
  * these uses are necessary to fulfill a legal obligation, a court order, or to exercise or defend legal claims;
  * these uses are necessary for protecting our legitimate interests or those of a third party, such as visitors, members or partners; 
  * you have expressly made this information public;
  * use of this information is in the public interest;
  * use of this information is sometimes necessary to protect your vital interests or the interests of others.   

Note that we rely primarily on consent to send marketing messages.   

When we process your information on the basis of legitimate interests, we do so as follows:   

The provision and improvement of our Services: We may use your information to improve and personalize our Services, and may share your information to achieve these purposes. We do this because it is necessary for exercising our legitimate interest in improving our Services for our users.   

It is also necessary for exercising our legitimate interest in understanding how our Services are used, as well as to explore and discover how we can grow our business. It is also necessary for exercising our legitimate interest of improving our Services, our efficiency, interest in our Services on the part of our users, and the gathering of information on the usage habits for our Services.    Maintaining the security of our Services: We may also use your information for security and safety purposes, and share your information to achieve these objectives. We do so as it is necessary for exercising our legitimate interest of ensuring the security of our Services, including better protecting our community against spam, harassment, violation of intellectual property, fraud and all other security risks.   

We respect your privacy. DoYouBuzz will not disclose your name, email address or other personal information to third parties without your consent, except in the conditions outlined in this policy.   

We use your information to provide and improve our Services and products, for billing and payments, for identification and authentication purposes, for targeted online marketing, for contacting members or interested parties and, in general, for research and aggregated reporting. For example, we can discover the types of products that interest you through your usage behavior and, as a result, suggest possible purchases.   

A fundamental aspect of our Services is our legitimate interest in personalizing your experience on the site, in order to help you discover Services, features, and Products that interest you, as well as recommend purchases.   

Legislation and security: DoYouBuzz may also retain or disclose your personal information to third parties in the limited following circumstances: in response to legal requests from public authorities, especially for responding to legitimate national security or law enforcement requirements; to protect, establish or exercise our legal rights or to defend ourselves against legal action, especially with respect to debt recovery; to comply with a subpoena, court order, court proceeding, or other legal requirement; or when we believe, in good faith, that a disclosure is necessary in order to comply with the law, prevent bodily injury, imminent financial loss, or to investigate, avoid or take action with respect to illegal activity, suspicion of fraud, threats to our property or violations of DoYouBuzz’s Terms of Service. In these particular cases, our use of your information may be necessary for the legitimate interest of a third party or ours to ensure the security of our Services, avoid harm or criminal activity, to assert or defend legal rights or prevent damages. This use may be necessary to fulfill a legal obligation, a court order, or to exercise or defend legal claims. It may also be necessary for public interest (for example, to prevent criminal activities) or to protect vital interests (in the unlikely event that we would have to share information to save lives or avoid bodily injury).   

If DoYouBuzz receives a legitimate and justified request to provide a member’s records or information on them in any of the limited circumstances described in the above paragraph, DoYouBuzz may disclose such personal information which may include, but is not limited to, the member’s name, physical address, telephone number, email address and company name.   

Aggregate information: DoYouBuzz may share demographic information with commercial or institutional partners, but it will be grouped and de-personalized so as not to reveal any personally identifiable information.   

Service providers: DoYouBuzz may also engage third-party companies and individuals (for example, companies responsible for the processing of payments, consulting firms, analytics and security providers) to assist us in the execution, provision, and sale of our Services. These third parties have limited access to your information, can only use it for performing tasks on our behalf, and are obligated to DoYouBuzz to not disclose or use your information for other purposes. Engaging service providers is often necessary to provide you with Services, especially when these companies play an important role, such as processing payments and shipments and helping us to ensure the operation and security of our Services. In other cases, these service providers are not strictly necessary for us to provide our Services to you, but instead help us to improve them by helping us to, for example, research how we can better serve our users. In these latter cases, we have a legitimate interest in working with service providers in order to improve our Services.   

Third parties: Third-party plug-ins may also collect information regarding your use of the Site. For example, when you upload a page on DoYouBuzz having a social plug-in from a third-party site or service, such as a “Like” or “Send” button, you also upload content from this third-party site. This site may request cookies directly from your browser. These interactions are subject to the privacy policies of the third-party sites. In addition, certain cookies and other similar technologies on the Site are used by third parties for online targeted marketing and other purposes. These technologies allow a partner company to recognize your computer or mobile device each time you use our Services. Be aware that when you use third-party sites or services, your use of these sites and services are subject to their own Terms of Use and privacy policies. DoYouBuzz chooses and manages these third-party technologies on its Site and in its Applications. However, these technologies are third-party and are subject to the third party’s privacy policy.   

##  16\. Security 

We value the security of your personal information. We apply current industry norms to protect the personal information that is provided to us, both during transmission and after receipt.   

We have put in place technical means, processes, regulations, internal training, and legal means to limit access to your personal information for the people and sub-contractors who need it to perform their job, by putting legal deterrents in place in case of breaches.   

Your account information is protected by a password. It is important that you protect your account and information against unauthorized access by carefully choosing your password and ensuring its security, as well as the security of your computer, for example, by logging out after you use our Services. If you have any questions regarding the security of your personal information, you can contact us at the following address: bonjour@doyoubuzz.com   

DoYouBuzz encrypts certain information using SSL (Secure Socket Layer) technology and various technological methods. DoYouBuzz applies current industry standards to protect the personal information provided to us, both during transmission and after receipt. Unfortunately, no method of transmission over the internet and no electronic storage method is 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. 

##  17\. Information Retention

DoYouBuzz will retain your information only for the duration necessary for the purposes outlined in this policy, as long as your account is active (i.e. during the life of your DoYouBuzz member account) as described in this policy, or for whatever duration is necessary in order to provide you with our Services.   

After two years of inactivity (i.e. no logging into the platform), users will receive a notice that their account will be deleted. After receiving additional alerts with no logins for two months afterward, the account will be permanently deleted.   

Note: the data stored by our sub-contractors will not be automatically deleted once the deletion of your information is requested. Sub-contractors complying with GDPR regulations are required to delete your data in a reasonable amount of time. You can also send us a specific request to delete your information, along with the sub-contractors (see the section labeled, “Your Rights”).   

If you wish for DoYouBuzz to stop using your information to provide you with our Services, you can close your account. DoYouBuzz will maintain and use your information to the extent necessary in order to comply with our legal obligations (for example, keeping your information in order to comply with tax laws having to do with revenue), resolve legal disputes, keep our commitments, and whatever is described elsewhere in this policy.   

##  18\. Security Backups 

In order to ensure the security and integrity of the information you give us, DoYouBuzz performs regular backups of your data using secure and automated protocols in separate, sealed infrastructures, located in other places. For these reasons, when you modify or delete your information, not all the data is immediately removed from all our backups (note, however, that they are thoroughly removed from the production environment, which means that the information you modify or delete will have an immediate impacted on our Services). The maximum duration of data retention in our backup after its modification or deletion is one month.   

We also keep log files for internal analysis. These log files are generally saved for a short period of time, except when they are used for site security, to improve site functionality, or if we are legally required to keep them for longer.

##  19\. Your rights 

You have a number of rights with respect to your personal information that we process. If you wish to manage, modify, limit or delete your personal information, you can do so through your DoYouBuzz account settings. If you wish to delete data stored by our sub-contractors, you can request do to so by contacting us, and we will assist you in whatever way possible. Upon request, DoYouBuzz will inform you if we have personal information belonging to you. By opening your account settings, you can access, correct, modify and delete certain personal information associated with your account. In certain cases, when we process your information, you may have the right to restrict or limit the various ways in which we use your personal information. In certain cases, you can also request the deletion of your personal data and receive a copy of this information in an easily accessible format. If you need additional help, you may contact DoYouBuzz via one of the communication channels listed in the “Contact Us” section below. We will respond to your request within a reasonable amount of time.   

If we process your information based on our legitimate interests as explained above, or in the interest of the public, you may object to this processing in certain circumstances. In such cases, we will cease to process your information unless we have legitimate reasons to do so, or where it’s necessary for legal reasons. When we use your data for direct marketing purposes, you can always object by using the link to unsubscribe from these communications, or by modifying your account settings.

##  20\. Withdrawal of consent 

If you have given your consent for us to process your information and for your use of our Services, you have the right to withdraw it. You can, for example, withdraw your consent to email marketing by using the link to unsubscribe from these communications, or by modifying your account settings. You may choose to withdraw your consent for the processing of your information and for your use of our Services at any time by closing your account using your account settings, and then send an email to bonjour@doyoubuzz.com to request that your information is deleted, with the exception of the information we are required to keep. This deletion is permanent (with the exception as explained in the “Security Backups” section, and your account cannot be restored.   

##  21\. Amendments to the Privacy Policy

From time to time, we may modify or update this policy. If we believe that the changes are significant, we will inform you of them by taking one (or more) of the following actions: (i) posting the changes on or through our Services, (ii) sending an email or message regarding the changes, (iii) posting an update in the latest DoYouBuzz newsletter. We encourage you to check back regularly for updates.   

##  22\. Contact us

If you have any questions, contact the DoYouBuzz support team through our Help Center.   
Send an email to Eric Cambray, Head of Data Protection: bonjour@doyoubuzz.com.   
Write to us at the following address:   

DoYouBuzz 

18, rue Scribe   
44000 Nantes   
France 

Updated May 24, 2018
